<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>{ federico-arias }</title>
    <link>https://federico-arias.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on { federico-arias }</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://federico-arias.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing a file upload handler in Golang</title>
      <link>https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/testing-upload-handler/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/testing-upload-handler/</guid>
      <description>There are multiple examples around the web about uploading a file in Go. Not so many about testing these type of handlers. Below, you can find an example of a simple way of testing your handler.
func TestUploadImage(t *testing.T) { //Set up a pipe to avoid buffering 	pr, pw := io.Pipe() //This writers is going to transform 	//what we pass to it to multipart form data 	//and write it to our io.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing research papers in Markdown with pandoc and LaTex (Part I: Style guide formatting)</title>
      <link>https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/pandoc-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/pandoc-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Those of us that have grown accustomed to the pristine simplicity of writing and coding in environments like Vim, Emacs or even Notepad dread the times when we are forced to use word processors like Microsoft Word, LibreOffice or Pages. This often happens when we need to write a research paper or some document that requires special formatting. Whether it be APA, MLA, The Chicago Manual of Style, or any other style guide, all of them present very specific demands regarding margins, font size, line height, citations and a myriad of other formatting options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A quick tip to format PDFs documents for e‑readers using the Linux command line</title>
      <link>https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/quick-tip-formatting-ereaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/quick-tip-formatting-ereaders/</guid>
      <description>Most e-book readers fail to display PDF documents in a legible font size, due to their inability to dynamically insert line breaks according to available width. Instead, you are forced to zoom-in and focus on only one portion of the document.
A way to solve this problem would be cutting the margins using pdfcrop. For example, if we wanted to remove 88 pts from both left and right margins we&amp;rsquo;ll do:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A comparative explanation of recursion in PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/postgres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/postgres/</guid>
      <description>One of PostgreSQL features that I had the most trouble getting my head around was the use of WITH RECURSION, particularly due to the fact that this type of recursion doesn&amp;rsquo;t resemble any of the examples of this concept that I had previously encountered. Even Postgres&amp;rsquo; documentation aknowledges this:
 Strictly speaking, this process is iteration not recursion, but RECURSIVE is the terminology chosen by the SQL standards committee.
 Let&amp;rsquo;s look at an example to see what we are talking about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://federico-arias.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://federico-arias.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Federico Arias, a freelance full-stack developer based on Latin America. I have experience working with the following tools:
 Front: Javascript (d3.js, React, Node), SCSS. Back: Scala, Python, Postgres, SQL Server, Golang, Linux. Tools: Git, Docker, Vim, R, Latex, XSLT.  I am also an experienced Technical Writer with a demonstrated history of working in the e-learning industry.
For the last 2 years, I have been working with companies specialized in the fields of Business Intelligence and Big Data Analytics, helping them gather, systematize and transfer knowledge through a wide variety of delivery mediums including video and online manuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Archive</title>
      <link>https://federico-arias.github.io/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://federico-arias.github.io/archive/</guid>
      <description> Sort by date or by category
-- {% for post in site.posts %} {{ post.date | date: &#34;%B %Y&#34; }}: {{ post.title }}  {% endfor %}  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hire me!</title>
      <link>https://federico-arias.github.io/hireme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://federico-arias.github.io/hireme/</guid>
      <description> I&#39;m open to relocation, remote or freelance work. Describe the main tasks involved in the box below and I&#39;ll get in touch with you as soon as possible.
If you are in a hurry, you can contact me at this number via WhatsApp: +56 9 4625 9752
.  your e-mail   how can I help you?   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>