<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on federico-arias</title>
    <link>https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on federico-arias</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing research papers in Markdown with pandoc and LaTex (Part I: Style guide formatting)</title>
      <link>https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/pandoc-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/pandoc-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Those of us that have grown accustomed to the pristine simplicity of writing and coding in environments like Vim, Emacs or even Notepad dread the times when we are forced to use word processors like Microsoft Word, LibreOffice or Pages. This often happens when we need to write a research paper or some document that requires special formatting. Whether it be APA, MLA, The Chicago Manual of Style, or any other style guide, all of them present very specific demands regarding margins, font size, line height, citations and a myriad of other formatting options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A quick tip to format PDFs documents for e‑readers</title>
      <link>https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/quick-tip-formatting-ereaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/quick-tip-formatting-ereaders/</guid>
      <description>Most e-book readers fail to display PDF documents in a legible font size, due to their inability to shrunk text to display a changing number of The only way of increasing a font for a PDF document is to zoom in and focus on only one portion of the file. A simple way to solve this is to
One would be tempted to solve this by cutting the margins with pdfcrop, but this will only result in old e-book readers displaying a pair of black stripes where margins used to be, due to the requirement of</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A comparative explanation of recursion in PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/postgres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://federico-arias.github.io/posts/postgres/</guid>
      <description>One of PostgreSQL features that I had the most trouble getting my head around was the use of WITH RECURSION, particularly due to the fact that this type of recursion doesn&amp;rsquo;t resemble any of the examples of this concept that I had previously encountered. Even Postgres&amp;rsquo; documentation aknowledges this:
 Strictly speaking, this process is iteration not recursion, but RECURSIVE is the terminology chosen by the SQL standards committee.
 Let&amp;rsquo;s look at an example to see what we are talking about.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>